Good to be with you. I'm Tony Dopal. The
breaking news right now.
Monster storm. A dangerous category 3
hurricane set to slam the Gulf Coast
with life-threatening storm surge and
devastating winds.
>> It's going to be a strong hurricane and
it's going to potentially do a lot of
damage.
>> More than 130 million in the impact
zone. The race to get out before
landfall tonight.
ICE outrage protest after a federal
immigration officer shot a man in a car
with his 5-year-old in the back seat.
What authorities are saying tonight
about why.
>> Panama rocked by a 7.7 magnitude
earthquake. The moment playing out on
live TV.
A man forever linked with Chicago.
Honoring an NFL hero, legendary Chicago
Bears coach Mike Dicka dead at 86.
>> I have him. He's breathing.
>> A house on fire with a man trapped
inside. The body cam video as police
rush in. Birds on a plane. The passenger
accused of smuggling batches of live
birds stuffed in his underwear. And
Steve Hartman goes on the road with a
woman on a mission to reunite lost dogs
with their humans. You
>> sweet boy
>> from CBS News headquarters in New York.
This is the CBS Evening News with Tony
Dopal.
>> And good evening. We begin tonight with
that category 3 hurricane just hours
from landfall along the Gulf Coast,
Pensacola Beach, Florida. As Hurricane
Isaas approaches shore, maximum
sustained winds near 115 mph. And the
National Weather Service warning of
life-threatening storm surge, possibly
up to 9 ft in some spots as the first
hurricane of the Atlantic storm season
closes in on Alabama and the Florida
panhandle. Our team is out there in the
middle of all of it. Starting with Jason
Allen in Gulf Shores, Alabama. Jason,
good evening.
>> Tony, good evening. And the intensity of
a storm this big is so evident in what
we are seeing here in Gulf Shores where
on the backside the wind is spinning and
so strong it's almost starting to calm
some of these 10 and 11 ft waves. And so
people here now are preparing for power
outages. They're preparing for flooding
and over the next several hours much
worse. Issa is bearing down on the Gulf
Coast, bringing with it dangerous surf,
damaging winds, heavy rain, and early
signs this powerful storm could leave
behind significant damage.
>> We're hoping to, you know, miss the
worst of it, but we have to be prepared
for the worst.
>> Orange Beach, Alabama is taking a
beating. Officials closed the water
because of potentially life-threatening
rip currents. This video taken inside
the center of the storm shows wave
heights of more than 30 feet during what
was supposed to be a busy weekend for
tourists. Streets and beaches were
empty. Gone is the gridlock from the
past 48 hours and the evacuation window
closed. This is one of the bridges, one
of the evacuation routes that takes
people away from the coastline. And law
enforcement tried to keep it open as
long as they could, but by midday the
winds were too strong. There was no time
left for people to evacuate. The few
residents left are trying to make the
best of it. Christy Woods manages one of
the only businesses still open, a wine
store.
>> We do take precautions. I mean, we're
kind of in the flood zone.
>> There's not much you can do other than
prepare the house best you can or leave.
>> Correct.
>> In Pensacola, shops are boarded up
trying to save windows from flying
debris. A storm surge up to 9 ft timed
with a high tide could flood areas well
inland from the coastline. Florida's
governor cautions about taking what's to
come lightly.
>> Folks who are in the path of this storm
should know um that this is not just
going to be a random tropical system.
It's going to be a strong hurricane and
it's going to potentially do a lot of
damage.
>> There are also potential impacts
offshore. Oil workers evacuated
platforms there. There are refineries in
the region. Any potential impact to
production or fuel prices is going to
depend on just how much potential damage
is done. Tony, Jason, thank you very
much. Let's get to meteorologist Rob
Marciano. He's in the Florida panhandle
tracking the hurricane and another
threat as well. A tropical storm
slamming parts of the West Coast. Rob,
good evening to you.
>> Hey, good evening, Tony. Well, needless
to say, the time to prepare and evacuate
is over because we're feeling the brunt
of Hurricane Eas right now. It is front
loaded. So, the front 50 miles of this
thing is where the most action is and
obviously it's coming in right now. The
center of this is due south of us by
about 50 miles and closing in at 17 18 m
an hour. So it's just a matter of 2,
three, maybe 4 hours before it makes
landfall. So what are the hazards in
play with this? Obviously the wind, the
rain on the on the right side of this.
We've got a tornado watch as that is up
until at least the uh 9:00 tonight,
probably beyond that. And then we're
looking at 15 ines of rain, 9 ft of
storm surge on not just the ocean side,
but on the bay side, too. that's just
loaded with all sorts of residents and
businesses there. If this thing comes
ashore, it does weaken, but it brings a
whole lot of rain with it all the way up
the eastern half of the country. Now, in
the west, we've got we've got Rachel
that's going to be uh make coming into
Southern California. There's a tropical
storm watch there for landfall tomorrow
night. You've already felt those massive
waves, that coastal flooding across
between Los Angeles and San Diego, and
that will only get get worse before this
thing makes landfall. So Tony, we are
getting squeezed on both sides of the
country by intense tropical cyclones.
>> All right, Rob, stay safe. We'll keep
watching it. Thank you. In other news, a
day after a federal immigration officer
shot a man in New York City with his
young son nearby, ICE is saying it was
the man who quote weaponized his
vehicle, forcing the officer to open
fire. CBS immigration correspondent
Camilo Mononttoya Galves reports.
Surveillance video shows two ICE
officers approaching Oscar Burggal's SUV
before Burggal drives away. Nearby,
people are seen ducking for cover.
Today, the NYPD released body camera
footage showing officers driving up to
the scene minutes after the shooting.
He's got a gun.
>> As the officers exit the car, a federal
agent can be seen wearing a reflective
vest and holding an assault style
weapon. The driver, Oscar Bergal, is
sitting on the ground in handcuffs, shot
once in the neck by an ICE agent, who,
according to the NYPD, fired seven times
into his car with Burggal's 5-year-old
child sitting in the back seat. The
officers then carried Burggal to a
patrol car. Professor
>> and took him to a nearby hospital.
Authorities say his child was unharmed.
DHS identified Burggal as a Dominican
national living in the US illegally and
with a criminal record, including a
lararseny conviction.
>> Mr. Bgal was a target of an HSI
investigation.
Mr. Brigal is associated with a gang.
>> Homeland Security Secretary Mark Way
Mullen admitted agents did not know a
child was in the car.
>> Oscar knew he had a child in his car.
Oscar chose to accelerate at a high rate
of speed and ram two different vehicles.
>> New York City's mayor called for ICE to
be abolished. A call echoed by scores of
protesters.
>> That's terrifying. Burgos lives in the
neighborhood
>> and as a parent I can't even imag sorry
I can't even imagine you know gunshots
going happening so close to my kids.
>> In a court hearing today Tony government
lawyers at the Justice Department
revealed that Bead was actually
transferred initially to New Jersey but
has since been brought back here to New
York City and is currently being held at
the Metropolitan Detention Center in
Brooklyn. His attorneys say that bullet
that struck him here behind us is still
inside of him. Tony Camo, thank you. We
turn now to scenes from a massive
earthquake today. This is southern
Panama, rocked by a 7.7 magnitude event,
shaking buildings more than 100 miles
away and toppling others entirely,
sparking a tsunami alert offshore. And
the moment even played out on live TV as
some broadcasters ran for cover.
And the Pentagon's plans to not only
execute the Fort Hood shooter, but to
live stream the event has even
Republicans divided. Tonight, our senior
White House and political correspondent
Ed O'Keefee has more.
>> President Trump today backed up defense
secretary Pete Hgs's plan to live stream
the execution of Nidal Hassan.
>> Death penalty through firing squad and
uh and he deserves it. Killed and
wounded many, many people, a maniac.
>> But Vice President JD Vance says he's
not interested in a live viewing.
>> Look, if it's ultimately live streamed,
I'm not going to be watching it. Only
Iran, Afghanistan, and Yemen have
carried out known public executions in
the last 5 years. Georgia Republican
Congressman Austin Scott says this is
what jihadists do. America is better
than that. The execution is scheduled
for December 3rd at 2 p.m. Eastern at
Fort Hood. The same time 17 years ago,
Hassan opened fire, killing 13 people
and wounding 32 more on the Texas base.
A massacre, he later said, was carried
out in support of the Taliban. People
need to understand that this is a
there's serious consequences for these
types of things.
>> This would be the first military
execution by firing squad since World
War II. One option the Pentagon may
consider is strapping Hassan, who's
paralyzed from the waist down, to a
specialized firing squad chair with
riflemen positioned a number of feet
away. Louisiana Republican Senator John
Kennedy.
>> I wouldn't I wouldn't teleise it or
publicize it or whatever they're doing.
I just think it makes it it makes our
society coarser.
Uh, and I wouldn't do it.
>> The president today also announced Katie
Zachariah will be the next White House
press secretary. She briefly served as
Homeland Security spokeswoman and has
been a frequent guest on conservative
news channels. Tony,
>> uh, and Ed, the president said he
reached an agreement with Vladimir Putin
to immediately import Russian diesel
fuel. What can you tell us? Yeah, the
president just last month signed a
sweeping Russia sanctions law that was
designed to restrict Russia's energy
supply, but now he's relaxing sanctions
on Russian diesel to try to bring down
prices ahead of the midterms. Putin has
agreed to immediately supply more than
300,000 tons of diesel. Ukraine's Vimir
Zolinsky criticized the deal, saying it
only fuels Putin's war effort. Tony,
>> Ed, thank you. It's a dangerous time to
be a public official in the US and we'll
be learning more about that this Sunday
as the director and deputy director of
the Secret Service give their first
joint interview to 60 Minutes.
>> How would you describe the current
threat environment in this country?
>> It's like we've never seen before. The
threats on our full-time protect are up
just over 40%
since they than they were last year.
That's a massive increase. Norah
O'Donnell joins us now with more from
that conversation. Norah, great to have
you here. So, what more did they tell
you about their ability to defend
against those threats?
>> There have been a lot of high-profile
failures by the Secret Service in the
past. That's why we wanted to talk to
them directly, see the types of changes
they're making. Number one, the Secret
Service has been dangerously
understaffed for years. They have their
largest recruitment class ever this
year. And on 60 Minutes, we're going to
take you behind the scenes into the
training facility to see not only how
they're staffing up for this election,
but 2028. You've got a presidential
election, all the candidates that they
have to take care of. You've got the
Olympics in 2028. So, there's a lot
going on for the service.
>> It's a big job, and the threats are
real. There are three known
assassination attempts against President
Trump. And I understand you learned more
about that first one as the Secret
Service learns more. That was Butler,
Pennsylvania, a gunman wounding the
president's ear. Look, there were a
series of failures that led to that day
that has been reported by Congress. A
hundred missed calls between local
police and the Secret Service. So, what
do they have now? A big truck that
travels in the motorcade so they can
communicate. Thomas Krooks, the gunman
who tried to kill President Trump and
Butler, Pennsylvania. He was able to fly
a drone for almost 10 minutes a couple
hours before that assassination attempt.
The Secret Service didn't detect it. So
now the Secret Service, one of their top
jobs is looking at drones. not only
surveillance but building offensive and
defensive capabilities. You'll see that
on Sunday on 60 Minutes.
>> That's the world we live in. So
interesting and so important as well.
Norah, thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> And you can see much more of that
interview this Sunday on 60 Minutes.
>> Mike Dick, the man and the myth. One of
the most recognizable personalities in
NFL history, died today at 86. He was a
Hall of Fame player, a Super Bowl
winning coach, and a pitch man for just
about everything. Our Mark Stman
remembers an icon.
>> Ah, shut up.
>> He was the real deal. A beloved tough
guy.
>> See that? That's your IQ, buddy. Zero.
>> All morning, Chicagoans reached out to
grieve. Did you hear Ditka?
>> He is considered a Bears sports legend.
And a Chicago sports legend.
>> Ditka smacks into a host of dark jerseys
and simply bulls his way through a maze
of tacklers. As number 89, a Hall of
Fame player, as a Super Bowl winning
coach, as a personality, Mike Ditka was
all bare.
>> Mike, why are you in such a bad mood?
>> What do you care?
>> Iron Mike was forged in a tough
Middletown, Alequipa, Pennsylvania.
Football got him out, but its fiery,
proudly bluecollar spirit never left
him.
>> We like our people. For those who don't
like our people, that's tough. We like
them. On SNL, D coach of the
>> became comic gold.
>> Ditka believed everyone has a destiny
and Chicago was his.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. And go
Bears.
>> Number 89 was 86. Mark Stman, CBS News.
Still ahead on the broadcast tonight,
with no time to spare and firefighters
yet to arrive, what police officers did
to reach a man trapped in a house fire.
We're back with a story of bravery in
the face of a houseire, but this time it
was the cops who ran in after arriving
first and learning someone could be
trapped inside. Here's our Chris Van
Cleave.
rushing towards danger. Dramatic new
body camera video captures the heroic
efforts of Co Pepper, Virginia police
responding to a house fire last Saturday
with a person possibly inside.
Officers raced into the house and up the
stairs towards the smoke.
>> Police department, if you're in here,
>> finding a locked bedroom door, one
officer used a pocket tool to quickly
pick the lock.
>> Somebody's inside.
>> Okay, go.
Then one of the officers crawled under
the thick black smoke, finding a man
unresponsive on his bed.
>> I HAVE HIM. HE'S BREATHING.
>> The officers pulled the man out of the
smoke, away from the fire, and to
safety.
>> HEY, WE NEED HELP.
>> Police say the resident was taken to an
area hospital before being transferred
to a burn unit. Three officers were
treated for smoke inhalation and
released. Chris Van Cleave, CBS News,
Washington.
Still ahead, the deep sea discovery that
reminded researchers of Spongebob
Squarepants. What they found.
A man arrested at the airport in Miami
this week had an unexplained bulge,
according to federal investigators. And
here's what they say it was. 10 birds
stuffed into tubes and hidden in his
underpants. The birds are okay, I'm
happy to learn. But the man faces
smuggling charges. Exotic birds
apparently can sell for thousands or
more. News for Spongebob fans. His
cartoon buddy Patrick Star was spotted
near Argentina. Not really him, of
course, but researchers have noted the
similarity and celebrated the sighting
amid 57 new species recently filmed and
photographed by a deep sea rover. All
never before seen in a Spongebob episode
or anywhere else. And it could have been
the end for a man in a sinking car near
Syracuse, New York. But a state trooper
responding to the call ran down a dock
next to the boat launch and used a
window punch to shatter the car's
sunroof. The driver got out with only
minor cuts. No word on how the car ended
up in the lake in the first place. Up
next, Steve Hartman takes us on the road
to meet a woman reuniting missing dogs
with their humans.
It's Friday, which means it's time to go
on the road where Steve Harbon has a
story of dogs lost and dogs found.
Christine Qua is a hunter of sorts,
often going deep into the woods around
Richmond, Virginia to track and trap
family members.
>> When someone loses their dog, that's
their child.
And that's why over the last few years,
Christine has captured dozens of lost
dogs.
She's part of a growing national network
of lost pet recovery specialists who
offer this service, often for free.
>> It's about being kind to other people
and doing what you wish people would do
for you. Her most recent case was a
desperate search for two golden doodles,
Bailey and Toby. They belonged to
66-year-old Annie Olip. Annie lost her
husband a couple years ago, and caring
for those dogs had become her purpose
until a few weeks ago when she got in a
bad car accident.
>> I thought, I'm going to go back to this
house and it's just going to feel so
empty.
Annie was driving in a heavy rain when
she hit a guardrail, flipped her car,
and almost died.
Her dogs were also in the car. They
survived, but they were missing.
>> Yeah, dogs typically are going to just
run away as quick as possible from the
commotion and look for quietness.
Christine used drones and trail cameras
to narrow the search, then set traps,
changed the food twice a day, and agreed
to stay on the case indefinitely. And
all this in addition to her day job in
software development.
>> So, you're constantly checking cameras,
you're sleeping in your car.
>> Yes.
>> This is bordering on obsession.
>> Absolutely. Again, the joy of seeing
them be reunited is ultimately what what
makes us keep going. In the end, it took
10 days to catch Toby,
16 days to catch Bailey. Put
>> your glasses on.
>> And no time at all for the tears to flow
once Annie saw her babies were back.
>> Oh my gosh, my precious.
Yes.
>> A
>> the three are now home together thanks
to that stranger who believes it takes a
village to raise a child. Even the furry
ones.
>> Sweet boy.
>> Steve Harper.
>> Sweet boy
>> on the road
>> in Richmond, Virginia.
>> Sweet boy.
>> Thank you, Steve. That's another day in
America and another week. I'm Tony
Dopal. For all of us here at CBS News,
thank you for watching this week. We'll
see you right back here on Monday. Good
night.